A Finding Aid to the Esther McCoy Papers, circa 1876-1990, bulk 1938-1989, in the Archives of American Art AAA.mccoesth
Archives of American Art
- Architect Files, 1912-1990; Series 6; (Boxes 26-28, 42; 2.2 linear feet)
  - Cetto, Max, circa 1951-1953, 1962-1963 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Ciampi, Mario, 1954-1964 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Coate, Roland, circa 1950s (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Craiker, Chris, 1979, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Eames, Charles and Ray (Box 26)
    - Interview Transcript, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Photographs, 1959-1962 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Printed Material, 1941-1944, 1966, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - Gehry, Frank (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1975, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Notes and Research Material, circa 1970s, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - Gill, Irving (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1989 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Notes and Writings, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 26, Folder 44-45)
    - Research Material, 1936, 1959-1989 (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - Goff, Bruce, 1968-1983 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - Grey, Elmer, 1953-1962 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - Harris, Harwell Hamilton (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1984 (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Research Material, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Harris, Murry, circa 1948-1949 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
  - Lautner, John, circa 1985-1988 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Le Corbusier, 1933, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Maybeck, Bernard, 1952, 1957, circa 1975 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Moore, Charles, 1968-1969, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Myers, Barton, circa 1977-1979 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Neutra, Richard and Dion (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1974 (Box 27, Folder 10-11)
    - Photographs, circa 1930s-1984; (Photographs by Julius Shulman not scanned) (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Research Material, circa 1950s-1967, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - O'Gorman, Juan (Box 27)
    - Clippings, 1953-1967; (oversized items housed in Box 42) (Box 27, Folder 14-15)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1984 (Box 27, Folder 16-18)
    - "The Degeneration of Architecture in Mexico Today" by Juan O'Gorman, 1954-1955 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Notes and Writings, circa 1942-1960s (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Otto, Frei, circa 1965-1966 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Pelli, Cesar (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1990 (Box 27, Folder 22-23)
    - Notes and Writings, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Research Material, 1968-1979 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Ponti, Gio (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1989 (Box 27, Folder 26-27)
    - Research Material, circa 1971 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Porset, Clara (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 29-30)
    - Photographs, circa 1952 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Research Material, 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Purcell, William (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, 1923-1964 (Box 27, Folder 33-34)
    - Notes and Research Material, circa 1946-1959 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Richards, Sim Bruce, 1960-1984 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Schindler, R. M. (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, circa 1920-1988 (Box 27, Folder 37-38)
    - Exhibition Documents, 1954, 1964-1967 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Notes, General, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 27, Folder 40-41)
    - Notes, Gregory Ain Interview regarding Schindler, undated (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Notes, "Talk with the Lovells,", 1958 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Photographs, 1912-1970s (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Research Material, Book of Documents, vol. I, circa 1949 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Research Material, Book of Documents, vol. II, circa 1949 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Research Material, General, 1922-1980 (Box 27, Folder 47-50)
    - Statements by Other Architects Regarding Schindler, circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Writings, [About Working for Schindler,], 1987 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Writings, "Schindler House Restoration,", undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Writings, Unidentified Draft Fragments, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Soriano, Raphael (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, circa 1961-1982 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Sorkin, Michael, 1979-1987 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Stenger, A. D., circa 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Sullivan, Louis, circa 1967 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Venturi, Robert (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1987 (Box 28, Folder 10-11)
    - Notes and Writings, circa 1975-1980 (Box 28, Folder 12-13)
    - Research Material, 1963-1983 (Box 28, Folder 14-16)
  - Victor Gruen Associates, circa 1965-1985 (Box 28, Folder 17-19)
  - Wachsman, Konrad, circa 1972-1977 (Box 28, Folder 20-23)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd (Box 28)
    - Notes and Research Material, circa 1950s (Box 28, Folder 24-25)
    - Photographs, circa 1950s (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Wright, Lloyd (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, circa 1959-1966 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - "Eric Wright Conversation,", 1979 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Notes and Writings, circa 1949-1960 (Box 28, Folder 29-30)
    - Research Material, 1965-1966 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Oversized Juan O'Gorman Clippings, 1953-1967; (Scanned with Box 27, Folders 14-15) (Box 42)
- Printed Material, circa 1885-1990; Series 7; (Box 28-31, 42; 2.9 linear feet)
  This series contains a large amount of printed material of interest to and collected by McCoy, much of it documenting her professional activities. Found here are books, clippings, magazines, postcards, newsletters, press releases, and publications by subject. News clippings include articles about McCoy, articles written by McCoy, articles about architecture not written by McCoy, and other miscellaneous subjects. Architecture, art, and literary magazines found here often include articles written by McCoy. Additionally, she collected leftist magazines such as New Masses and Left Front. Certain printed materials are arranged by subjects which were of interest to McCoy for her writing projects. Included are printed materials gathered during her travels to Italy, Mexico, and Israel. These files may contain brochures, exhibition announcements and catalogs, booklets, travel guides, newsletters and other miscellaneous items.
  Portions of this series has been scanned. Items not directly relating to McCoy's career as a writer and architectural historian have not been scanned.
  This series has been arranged alphabetically by type of item followed by an alphabetical arrangement of subject files. Items within each folder are arranged chronologically. Researchers should note that additional printed materials, especially clippings, are also found in Series 4: Architectural Writings, Series 5: Projects, and Series 6: Architect Files.
  - Books, The Chapbook: A Miscellany, 1924 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - Books, Course in Making Mosaics, by Josef L. Young, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Books, The Dance of Death by Hans Holbein, 1898 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Books, Dante's Inferno by Dante Alighieri, Illustrated by M. Gustave Doré, circa 1885 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Books, Dorothy M. Richardson by John Cowper Powys, 1931 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - Books, Gentlemen Prefer Blondes by Anita Loos, 1925 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Books, The Human Tragedy by Anatole France, circa 1920s (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Books, Le Poém ?lectronique by Le Corbusier, circa 1958 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - Books, Little Blue Book, No. 659, "The Lost Phoebe" and "Old Rogaum and His Theresa" by Theodore Dreiser, 1918 (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - Books, Studies in Pessimism by Arthur Schopenhaur, undated (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - Book Proofs, Cliff May, Western Ranch Houses Vol. II, circa 1985; (Oversized items housed in Box 42) (Box 28, Folder 42)
  - Book Proofs, Unidentified, undated (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Calendars, War Resistance League, 1983-1984 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, About Architecture (Not written by McCoy), circa 1937-1989 (Box 29, Folder 2-5)
  - Clippings, About Esther McCoy, circa 1925, 1928, 1958-1990 (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
  - Clippings, Arts and Architecture Title Pages (Photocopies), 1940-1967 (Box 29, Folder 8-12)
  - Clippings, Writings by Esther McCoy, 1936-1954 (Box 29, Folder 13-16)
  - Clippings, Writings by Esther McCoy, 1955-1959; (oversized items housed in Box 42) (Box 29, Folder 17-20)
  - Clippings, Writings by Esther McCoy, 1960-1988 (Box 29, Folder 21-23)
  - Clippings, Writings by Esther McCoy, undated (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1926-1984 (Box 29, Folder 25-29)
  - Magazines (Box 29)
    - The Architectural Digest, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Architectural Record, 1957-1964 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Evergreen Review, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Historic Preservation, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - L. A. Architect, 1977, 1987-1988 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Left Front, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Museos Y Arte De Mexico, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - New Masses, 1934-1936 (Box 29, Folder 37-41)
    - New Mexico Quarterly, 1955, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Pacific Weekly, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Partisan Review & Anvil, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Plain Talk, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - Miscellaneous Architecture Magazines, 1957, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous Architecture Magazines, 1968-1984; (Oversized items housed in Box 42) (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Art Magazines, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Magazines, General, 1961, 1969, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Literary Magazines, 1925, 1933-1947, 1958; (partially scanned) (Box 30, Folder 4-6)
    - Miscellaneous Socialist Magazines, 1966, 1967, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, 1968, 1970, 1982, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, Council for Planning and Conservation, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Postcards from Travels (Blank), circa 1940s-1970s (Box 30, Folder 10-11)
  - Press Releases, 1979, 1981-1986 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Publications by Subject (Box 30)
    - Architecture and Urban Design, 1939-1989; (oversized items housed in Box 42) (Box 30, Folder 13-19)
    - Artists, circa 1936-1988 (Box 30, Folder 20-24)
    - California (Historical and Cultural Landmarks), 1956-1975 (Box 30, Folder 25-27)
    - Cast Iron, circa 1973-1976 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Israel, 1960-1970 (Box 30, Folder 29-30)
    - Italy, 1930-1972 (Box 30, Folder 31-33)
    - Italy, 1930-1972; (oversized items housed in Box 42; not scanned) (Box 31, Folder 1-10)
    - Labor, 1932-1942 (Box 31, Folder 11-13)
    - Mexico, 1947-1968; (oversized items housed in Box 42) (Box 31, Folder 14-15)
    - Southern California Institute of Architecture, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Theatre, 1920-1936 (Box 31, Folder 17-18)
  - Tour Brochures, 1951-1954 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1935-1985 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Oversized Book Proofs, Cliff May, Western Ranch Houses Vol. II, circa 1985; (See also Box 28, Folder 41) (Box 42)
  - Oversized Clippings, Writings by Esther McCoy, 1956-1957; (See also Box 29, Folders 17-20) (Box 42)
  - Oversized Miscellaneous Architecture Magazines, 1986; (See also Box 30; Folder 1) (Box 42)
  - Oversized Printed Material on Architecture and Urban Design, 1939-1989; (See also Box 30, Folders 13-19) (Box 42)
  - Oversized Printed Material on Italy, 1930-1972; (See also Box 31, Folders 1-10) (Box 42)
  - Oversized Printed Material on Mexico, 1947-1968; (See also Box 31, Folders 14-15) (Box 42)
- Artwork, 1924-1967, undated; Series 8; (Box 31; 0.4 linear feet)
  This series contains several minor prints and drawings collected by McCoy. Many of the drawings are by unidentified artists. Of note are a drawing of Esther McCoy by Esther Rollo, ink drawings by Forrest Wilson, and etchings which McCoy purchased, including several by Thomas Worlidge.
  Items are arranged alphabetically by folder heading.
  - Artwork sent to Esther McCoy, 1967, undated (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Decorative Paper, undated (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Drawing of Esther McCoy by Esther Rollo, circa 1963 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Drawings by Forrest Wilson, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Drawings by Unidentified Artists, 1924, undated (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Etching by A. Brunet-Debaines, undated (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Etching by Albrecht Durer, undated (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Etching by S. Le Clerc, undated (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Etchings by Thomas Worlidge, undated (Box 31, Folder 29-33)
  - Etching by Unidentified Artist, undated (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Hardy Hanson, 1961-1965 (Box 31, Folder 35)
- Photographs and Slides, circa 1876-1989; Series 9; (Boxes 31-38, 41-46, 51; 8.7 linear feet)
  Most of the photographs arranged in this series are of architects, architecture, and related research subjects, and were taken by McCoy and others in support of her numerous articles, books, and exhibitions. Also included are McCoy's personal and family photographs. In addition, there are approximately 3,600 slides used by McCoy in her numerous lectures and talks.
  The series is arranged as 6 subseries:
  9.1: Personal and Family Photographs, circa 1876-1989
  9.2: Architects, circa 1898-1980s
  9.3: Case Study Houses, circa 1945-1962
  9.4: Exhibition Photographs, circa 1952-1969
  9.5: Research Photographs, circa 1915-1970s
  9.6: Slides, circa 1950s-1980s
  - Personal and Family Photographs, circa 1876-1989; 9.1
    Found here are photographs of McCoy, her family, and friends. Included are many portraits and snapshots of McCoy, as a child and adult, as well as snapshots of her with her sister Ruth, other family members, her husband Berkeley Tobey, and various friends. Also found are photographs of McCoy and Tobey family members, dating back to the 1870s. Most photographs of family and friends are unidentified. Included are photographs of her colleague and editor of Arts and Architecture, John Entenza; photographs of artist Margeurite Wildenhain at Pond Farm; and photographs of Theodore Dreiser, Albert (Tim) Robert, Ray Eames, John Collier, and Reyner Banham.
    This subseries also includes three photograph albums. One album contains photographs of McCoy from the age of 12 to 16, her sister Ruth, and childhood friends and family. The other two albums document awards dinners honoring McCoy. The Vesta Awards album also serves as a guest book for the event and includes photographs of each guest and brief handwritten notes to McCoy.
    This subseries has been scanned in its entirety except for negatives.
    - Photographs of Esther McCoy, 1905-circa 1939 (Box 31, Folder 36-37)
    - Photographs of Esther McCoy, 1940s (Box 31, Folder 38-39)
    - Photographs of Esther McCoy, 1950s (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Photographs of Esther McCoy, 1960-1989 (Box 32, Folder 3-4)
    - Photographs of Esther McCoy by Deborah Sussman, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
    - Esther McCoy School Photographs, 1911-circa 1916 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Esther McCoy School Photographs, circa 1920; (Rolled Photographs) (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Esther McCoy with Family and Friends, circa 1910-1989 (Box 32, Folder 8-12)
    - Photographs of Esther McCoy with Berkeley Tobey, 1920s, 1941-1950s (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Photographs of Berkeley Tobey, 1887, 1914-1956 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Photographs of Esther McCoy's Sister, Ruth, 1917-circa 1920 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Photographs of the McCoy Family, circa 1876-1953 (Box 32, Folder 16-21)
    - Photographs of the Tobey Family, 1879-circa 1950s (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Photographs of Family and Friends, circa late-1800s-1950s (Box 32, Folder 23-28)
    - Photographs of Friends, circa 1960s-1989 (Box 32, Folder 29-30)
    - Photographs of John Entenza, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Photographs of Esther McCoy's 80th Birthday Party, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 32-34)
    - Photographs of Coffeyville Lumber Co., circa 1887-early 1900s (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Photographs of J. E. McCoy General Store, late-1800s (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - Photographs of McCoy Family Houses, circa 1910-1953 (Box 32, Folder 37)
    - Photographs of Frank McCoy's Funeral, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 38)
    - Photographs of Marguerite Wildenhain at Pond Farm, circa 1949 (Box 32, Folder 39)
    - Travel Snapshots, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 32, Folder 40)
    - Photographs of Long Beach Earthquake and Santa Monica Flood Damage, 1933, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 41)
    - Photograph Albums (Box 32)
      - Loose Pages from an Album, circa 1915-1920 (Box 32, Folder 42)
      - Album, 1916-1920 (Box 32, Folder 43)
      - Schindler House Dinner Honoring Esther McCoy, 1980s (Box 32, Folder 44)
      - Vesta Awards (Dismantled), 1987 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Vesta Awards, Loose Items, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous and Unidentified Photographs, circa 1900-1960s (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Negatives, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 33, Folder 4-5)
    - Copyprints of Negatives, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
    - Negatives, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Architects, circa 1898-1980s; 9.2
    Found here are photographs of works by architects, which McCoy compiled for her books, exhibition catalogs, articles, and other professional projects. Photographs primarily depict architecture by Southern California architects, but also including works by architects working elsewhere in the United States, Italy, and Mexico. Some of these photographs also document architecture by young architects working in the U.S. during the mid-1960s. Photographs depict various interior and exterior views, construction, and occasionally found are photographs of the architect. A large number of photographs found here depict the work of Gregory Ain, Luis Barragan, J. R. Davidson, Irving Gill, Bernard Maybeck, Juan O'Gorman, R. M. Schindler, and Raphael Soriano. Photographs were taken by Esther McCoy, prominent architectural photographers Marvin Rand and Julius Shulman, and many others.
    The bulk of this subseries has been scanned. Photographs taken by Julius Shulman and Marvin Rand have not been scanned and are noted in the folder heading.
    Files are arranged alphabetically by name of architect; works by that architect are arranged chronologically by construction date. Date of construction is included in parentheses when it is known. When only one or two photographs represent the work of an architect, it was placed in a file of "Miscellaneous Architects, A-Z." Researchers should note that additional photographs of architects and architecture can be found in Series 4: Architectural Writings, Series 5: Projects, and Series 6: Architect Files.
    - Abell, Thornton, Unidentified House, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Ain, Gregory (Box 33)
      - Photographs of Gregory Ain, circa 1950, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - Edwards House (1936), circa 1940s; (Photographs by Marvin Rand have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Ernst House (1937), circa 1960s (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Scharlin House (1937), circa 1940 (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Dunsmuir Flats (1937-1938), 1939-1960s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - Becker House (1938), circa 1960s (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Beckman House (1938), circa 1960s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - Vorkapinch House (1938), circa 1960s (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - Daniel House (1939), circa 1960s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Hay House (1939), circa 1960s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 19)
      - Tierman House (1939), circa 1960s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - Community Homes, Reseda (1945-1949), circa 1949 (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - Avenel Cooperative Housing (1948), circa 1950s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 22)
      - Mar Vista Housing (1948), circa 1950s; (Photographs by Marvin Rand have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 23)
      - Miller House (1948), circa 1950s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 24)
      - Wilfong House (1949), circa 1950s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 25)
      - Museum of Modern Art, Women's Home Companion Exhibition House (1950) (Box 33, Folder 26)
      - Various Projects, 1929-1957, 1971; (photographs by Julius Shulman and Marvin Rand have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 27-30)
      - Unidentified Projects, undated; (Photographs by Marvin Rand have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Artigas, Francisco, Various Projects, circa 1960s (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - Barnes, Edward Larrabee, Hallmark House, circa 1965 (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - Barragan, Luis (Box 33)
      - Photographs of Luis Barragan, circa 1960s (Box 33, Folder 34)
      - Barragan House (1947-1948), circa 1948; (Oversized Items housed in Box 42) (Box 33, Folder 35)
      - Jardines del Pedregal (includes Alfred Ortega House), circa 1940s-1950s; (Oversized Items housed in Box 42) (Box 33, Folder 36)
      - Prieto Lopez House, undated; (Oversized Items housed in Box 42) (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - Birkerts, Gunnar, Tougaloo College (1965), circa 1965 (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - Birkerts, Gunnar, Various Projects, circa 1960s (Box 33, Folder 39)
    - Blair, Donald and Saul Zaik, Salishan Village, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 40)
    - Blake, Pater and Alan Chapman, Beach House, circa 1959 (Box 33, Folder 41)
    - Blake, Peter and Julian Neski, Martinez House (1957), circa 1957; (Photographs by Hans Namuth have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 42)
    - C. F. Murphy Associates, Blue-Cross Blue-Shield Building, Chicago, circa 1970s (Box 33, Folder 43)
    - C. F. Murphy Associates, Chicago Civic Center (1965), circa 1965 (Box 33, Folder 44)
    - Candela, Felix (Box 33)
      - Inglesia de la Virgen Milagrosa (1954), circa 1954 (Box 33, Folder 45)
      - Chapel Coyoacou, circa 1950s (Box 33, Folder 46)
      - Mexican House (Transparencies), circa 1950s (Box 33, Folder 47)
      - Various Projects, circa 1950s-1960s; (photographs by Marvin Rand have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 48-49)
    - Cetto, Max, Cetto House, Jardines del Pedregal (1949), circa 1949 (Box 33, Folder 50)
    - Cetto, Max, Various Projects, circa 1950 (Box 33, Folder 51)
    - Cheval, Ferdinand, Le Palais Idéal (1923), circa 1960s (Box 33, Folder 52)
    - Ciampi, Mario J., Various Projects, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 33, Folder 53)
    - Clements, Stiles O., Richfield Oil Building (1929), circa 1950s; (Photographs by Marvin Rand have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 54)
    - Corbett, Mario, Unidentified House, circa 1950 (Box 33, Folder 55)
    - Davidson, J. R. (Box 33)
      - Photographs of J. R. and Greta Davidson, 1902, 1922, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 56)
      - Pfeifferling House (1919), circa 1919; (oversized items housed in Box 43) (Box 33, Folder 57-58)
      - Hi-Hat Restaurant (1929), circa 1929 (Box 33, Folder 59)
      - Hotel Shoreland (1937), circa 1937; (Oversized items housed in Box 43) (Box 33, Folder 60)
      - Maitland House (1937), circa 1937; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 61)
      - Sardis Restaurant (1937), circa 1938; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 62)
      - Stothart House (1937), circa 1930s-1940s; (Photographs by Marvin Rand have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 63-65)
      - Berkson House (1939), circa 1940s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 66)
      - Gretna Green Apartments (1940), 1941-1944; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 67)
      - Thomas Mann House (1941), circa 1940s (Box 33, Folder 68)
      - Vigeveno House (1941), circa 1940s; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 69)
      - Joseph Kingsley House (1946), circa 1948-1951; (Photographs by Julius Shulman have not been scanned) (Box 33, Folder 70)